Jason Spiller

303.522.5424

jason@jasonspiller.com www.jasonspiller.com www.github.com/jasonspiller www.linkedin.com/in/jason-spiller



Front-End Developer

Highly passionate developer / designer with an extensive background in creating interactive web and mobile experiences. Vast UI / UX background in front-end development with a focus on semantic HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Dedicated to successful implementations of engaging and usable connected experiences.

JavaScript / jQuery React / Bootstrap Git / GitHub / Heroku / mLab HTML / HTML5 User Interaction Design / UI Node.is / npm Mongo / Mongoose CSS / Sass User Experience Design / UX

Professional Experience

Freelance Developer Foxhound Digital, Remote July 2018 to Current

- Developed and integrated a mobile-first service booking widget using JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, and PHP resulting in an over 500% increase in leads, 200% growth in bookings, and a 7-fold boost to recurring revenue.
- Multiple WordPress sites with advanced CSS animations, mobile-friendly layouts, and MailChimp integration.

Design Lead FRONTSTEPS, Denver, Colorado February 2007 to July 2017

Turn-key CMS websites provided as SaaS for HOAs and their management companies.

- Wrote over 100 custom JavaScript / jQuery scripts to add customizations to websites for turn-key custom CMS.
- Worked with both internal and external stakeholders, championing usability, prototyping, and coding pixelperfect layouts using clean HTML, CSS, and graphic assets for over 50 client-facing interfaces and features.
- Designed, prototyped and coded over 15 interfaces for an innovative mobile app that made it possible for thousands of Property Managers to easily and efficiently capture HOA violations.
- Managed an average of 30 simultaneous projects designing and coding the front-end for more than 60 custom websites designs per year ranging from small HOA boards to million-dollar management companies.

Training

Web Development Immersive General Assembly, Denver, Colorado March 2018 to June 2018 480 hours in-class with 250 hours of outside individual and team projects.

- Find Your Toys Full stack application that allows a user to search only the best toy stores. Users can sign up and manage their searches. Express, Mongo, Mongoose, Sass, Node, EJS, Bootstrap, JS, Google Search API
- Movie Beatdown Mobile game that allows you to sort the American Film Institute's Top 100 movies using one-on-one battles. OAuth, Mongo, Mongoose, Sass, Node, EJS, Bootstrap, JS, Open Movie Database API
- Sell Your Toys Completely decoupled full stack classifieds application with free text search and filterable results. React, Bootstrap, Sass, ¡Query, Express, Mongo, Mongoose, SendGrid Email API

Education

B.S. in Web Application Development Metropolitan State University of Denver - 4.0 GPA B.F.A. in Visual Design emphasis in Interactive Studies New Mexico Highlands University - 3.83 GPA

Extra-Curriculars

Volunteered for Develop Denver, Angular Denver, WordCamp Denver, and attended 50+ meetups in 2018.